Eskinder G. Gezahagne

eskinderget@gmail.com

github: http://www.github.com/eskinderg

http://www.eskinder.net

As confirmed by my portfolio content and code, I combine my knowledge, experience and skills with technology in order to develop professional and innovative web applications.

I follow OAUTH, REST and SOLID software engineering principles. I am also a fan of TDD, Agile, 12-Factor App and Block-Element-Modifier methodologies. I use after-release error logging to ensure applications are bug-free.

By following the best practices, I produce clean code which is comprehensive, easy to debug and maintain.

I have been passionate with development since childhood and enjoy learning about the latest technological advancements.

- Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of professional experience in the design & development of web application, implementation of Object-Oriented Design (OOD) in Angular 2/4+ and C#.
- Proficiency in developing front-end Single Page Application (SPA) using Angular 2/4+, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Typescript, and jQuery.
- Proficient in Angular 2/4+, Angular Material and worked as MEAN Stack developer.
- Proficient in developing web applications using Node.js, Express.js and MVC.
- Experience in Web API, MVC, N-Tier Architecture, Relational Database Design, and Non-Relational Database Design.
- In-depth knowledge & experience of software Design Patterns including Singleton, Prototype, Factory, and Unit of Work & Repository Pattern.
- Experience in Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) and Object-Data Modeling (ODM) using ADO.NET, Entity Framework, LINQ and Lambda expression.
- Experience in design and implement of Relational Database including Normalization, Stored Procedures, Triggers, Views, User Defined Functions, SSIS Packages and SSRS Packages in MS SQL Server.
- Proficient in writing test cases and using unit tests including NUnit and Jasmine to validate development releases with Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodology.
- Proficient in Agile, JIRA and Waterfall SDLC methodologies.
- Proficient in Software Configuration Management, Source Control and Version Control using tools such as Git and Team Foundation Server (TFS).

Education

- Bachelor's (B.S.c) in Computer Science & Information Technology from Arba-Minch University, Ethiopia (11/2008).
- · Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP).
- Microsoft Certified C# Programming Specialist.

Technical Skills

- Front End Languages: Angular 2/4+, JQuery, SAAS, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript.
- Back End Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC.
- Testing Frameworks: Mocha, Jasmine, Sinon.
- Database Systems: MySQL, MS-SQL.
- Cloud Computing: Amazon Web Service (AWS).
- Code Quality: Code Climate
- Application IDE: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, VIM, Neovim.
- Versioning Tool: Git.
- Webservers: Apache, http-server, IIS, ExpressJS.
- SEO: Google Analytics.
- Full Understanding of OOP.
- ASP.Net MVC 5 using Entity Framework and modern architectural patterns.

· RESTful API programming.

Professional Experience

Freelance Full Stack Developer (09/2018)

Full Stack Web Developer

- Created SPA, user interactive (UI) web pages using web technologies like HTML5, SASS, Typescript, Angular2 and Bootstrap.
- Created and used Reducers that received Actions to modify the store State.
- Created Action dispatch to deploy Actions to add Dynamic Functionality
- Created custom NPM modules.
- Developed administrative UI Components using Angular2, Typescript and Webpack
- Used Bootstrap for Responsive Web design.
- Optimized Front-end assets for speed and performance
- Used Middleware, Redux-Promise in application to retrieve data from Back-End and to also perform RESTFUL services.
- Created custom Angular Components including Breadcrumbs, Reactive Forms, Form Validators, Tabbed Components and Toggle Buttons.

Nuaxis (09/2016 - 07/2018)

Front End Developer

- Created programs as per user / design requirements using AngularJS.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams (DEV, UX/UI & BA) to define, design, and deliver creative digital solutions.
- Utilized, automated unit tests and integration tests for application life cycle.
- Executed Agile Developmental techniques.
- Utilized industry best practices to create effective business solutions for clients.
- Participated and contributed towards senior-level technology discussions.
- Created web forms using section 508 and US web standards.
- Used Git flow techniques for feature branching, merging and continuous integration.
- Implemented Google Analytics using Angularitics.
- Participated on OAuth implementation for user's role and permissions using JWT (JSON web token).
- Created migration scripts for Postgres database systems using Sequelize ORM.
- Consumed back-end web API.
- Produced reports and statistical information for managers using code climate, and mocha testing framework.
- Used bootstrap CSS to create, modify and update web layouts.
- Created angular 1.5 components and directives for front-end validation and routing.
- Used Node JS schema validator for backend validation.
- Performed unit and integration test for front-end and back-end systems using AngularJS and NodeJS.

Bloomberg BNA (11/2015 - 07/2016)

Software Engineer II

- E commerce development using Agile methodologies.
- Full Stack web development using ASP .Net MVC, C#, Angularjs and MSSQL.
- Provide support for legacy applications and strategic migration planning for internal legacy web application.
- Integrate Asp MVC with Ektron system.
- Design modern architectural patterns for new and legacy systems.
- Write Front-end, Back-end Unit Tests that for re factoring existing code and for continuous integration deployment process.
- Provide statistical information for senior managers.

Freelance (02/2013 - 11/2014)

Freelance Web Developer

- Full Stack development using LAMP stack.
- Word Press theme customization.

Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia. (09/2009 - 01/2013)

Web Developer

- Design visual layout of websites.
- Create Stored Procedures using MSSQL.
- Test a website before it goes live and identify problems.
- Advise users on the functionality of the website.
- Change code of an existing website using MVC, C#, Entity Framework and LINQ technologies.
- Optimize web assets for optimal speed and performance
- Produce reports and statistical information for senior managers

HST Consulting, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (05/2010 - 05/2011)

System Administrator

- Maintaining configuration of network equipment's and web services.
- Managing Active Directory Users and Computers.
- Managing network protocols, file sharing services, file backups and intranet web services.